Contact

San Diego, CA 92122 949-466-2546 AliSarkeshik@gmail.com

Education

UCSD Certificate, Full Stack Web Development February 2019 to August 2019

UC Riverside Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

<u>LinkedIn</u>

www.linkedin.com/in/alisarkeshik

Technical Skills

JavaScript

jQuery

HTML

Node.js

_ .

React.js

MySQL

Publications

https://urlzs.com/Su7nh

Ali Sarkeshik

Summary

Solutions-driven Full Stack Developer/Software Engineer who uses ingenuity and creativity to build fluid and functional web applications. My previous experience includes method development in Chemistry and Instrumentation (hardware and software troubleshooting) in a resale and OEM environment.

Experience

UC San Diego Extension Full Stack Developer February 2019 - Present

<u>Projects</u>: https://alisarkeshik.github.io/UpdatedPortfolio/portfolio.html

- JavaScript Trivia Game
- ➤ GifTastic (using AJAX)
- Amazon Manager: MySQL, Node.js, Inquirer, Express
- > Train Scheduler: Firebase

Group Projects

TravelGuide: AJAX, API's, JavaScriptPubCrawl: MySQL, Node.js, JavaScript

GitHub: https://github.com/AliSarkeshik

Certificate program learning front-end and back-end technologies through a dynamic curriculum:

Database Theory, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, MongoDB, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Bookshelf.js, AJAX, Firebase, Command Line, Heroku, and Git.

PerkinElmer, Inc. Customer Support Engineer June 2018 - December 2018 San Diego, CA

- Provided on-site personalized support services for PerkinElmerinstruments
- Provided troubleshooting expertise and repair skills needed to help identify and resolve issues related to hardware, software or applications support.
- Performed PMs, installs, and repairs on various Perkin Elmer instruments (Janus, LabChip, SciClone, Zephyr, and Euroimmune products).

Roche Diagnostics
Planned Activities Specialist/Field Service Engineer
January 2018 - May 2018
Greater San Diego Area (Contract position via Tailored Management)

- Performed on-site preventative maintenance, installation, and technical updates (TSB's) on company products (Cobas 6000 and 8000 analyzers).
- Diagnosed mechanical, hardware, software and system failures.

Trained in: CD Foundations of Hardware, IT Products, c6000/8000 Service Operator Training, and Cobas 6000 Install/Core Service.

BioSurplus, Inc. Service Engineer January 2017 - July 2017 San Diego, CA

- Determined the re-sale viability of company acquisitions.
- Diagnosed, repaired, and serviced a wide range of laboratory equipment.
- Systems included but were not limited to: Flow Cytometry, Centrifuges, Refrigeration Systems, Automated Liquid Handlers, and HPLC.

Versum Materials (Formerly known as Air Products and Chemicals, Inc.) Analytical Chemist November 2013 - January 2017

Carlsbad, CA (Contract Position via The Fountain Group: Nov 2013 – May 2015)

- Worked closely with a team of researchers to support method development for new semi-conductor products.
- Performed hands on installation (hardware/software), calibrations, troubleshooting, and maintenance on GC instruments (Agilent 5973/6850/6890/Thermo Trace 1310).
- GC-TCD/GC-FID, GC-MS, DIP-MS analysis of organo silanes and GC-PHID analysis of Octane
- Successfully assisted in transitioning R&D products to commercial status (ISO: 9001:2008, 17025, 10012)

Additional Experience:

BP (British Petroleum) Research Associate March 2013 - October 2013

Ionis Pharmaceuticals (Formerly ISIS Pharmaceuticals) Research Associate/Scientist - Oligo Synthesis October 2012 - November 2012

The Scripps Research Institute Research Technician July 2006 - July 2011